<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Adventures of a wannabe geek!]]></title>
  <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-28T13:08:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paul Stack (@stack72)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps and .Net Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2015/10/28/devops-and-net-conference/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-28T12:29:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2015/10/28/devops-and-net-conference</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I just tweeted the following,</p>

<p><img src="http://paulstack.co.uk/images/DevOpsTweet.png" alt="Image" /></p>

<p>Firstly, I&rsquo;d like to say that this is <em>not</em> about naming and shaming. Secondly, I am not annoyed with the conference at all about the response. The conference I spoke to advertises itself as “engineering talks only” so I wanted to post a few things about that.</p>

<p>In my opinion, the writing of code and the ecosystem of a specific platform is only 10% (or rather a small portion) of what we need to be aware of as software engineers. I am a software developer who works in the infrastructure / ops world now. When I was writing application only code, I was not involved in understanding the entire ecosystem of the software I was working on. In hindsight, I really feel I missed out by not being part of it. Since being part of the infrastructure world, I feel it has actually helped me develop better &amp; more robust software.</p>

<p>Organising conferences is a huge amount of work and is, frankly, hard. I understand that conferences cannot cater for every part of an ecosystem. One thing I do think conferences should do, is to strive to make developers better. DevOps, Continuous Delivery and Infrastructure are / should be things that we, as developers, care about. To dismiss these style of topics from a conference that advertises for “engineering talks only” can help to hinder developers from delivering the best products they can. It may not also make developers understand the importance of software being in production and making money</p>

<p>Food for thought…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recommended Ops Books]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2015/04/09/recommended-ops-books/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-09T10:50:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2015/04/09/recommended-ops-books</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I created a Github repo to store all the book recommendations I have had since moving more into the operations space. The book categories (so far), include:</p>

<ul>
<li>DevOps / Culture</li>
<li>Continuous Delivery</li>
<li>Systems Thinking</li>
<li>Web Operations</li>
<li>System Architecture</li>
<li>Tooling</li>
</ul>


<p>I want this repository to continue to grow with a list of links to books that people would recommend. If you feel you want to make some recommendations, then please feel free to send a PR!</p>

<p>Otherwise, enjoy the <a href="https://github.com/stack72/ops-books">suggestions</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for a new role]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2015/03/04/looking-for-a-new-role/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-04T14:20:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2015/03/04/looking-for-a-new-role</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>EDIT: I am no longer looking for a new role. Thanks to all for the suggestions</p>

<p>TL;DR: I am looking for a new role. I am an infrastructure developer who has a passion for metrics, monitoring and alerting. If you feel that you are interested in me coming to help your engineering team, then get in contact with me</p>

<p><a href="public@paulstack.co.uk"><a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#112;&#117;&#98;&#x6c;&#105;&#x63;&#x40;&#x70;&#97;&#117;&#x6c;&#115;&#x74;&#x61;&#x63;&#x6b;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#46;&#117;&#107;">&#x70;&#117;&#98;&#108;&#105;&#99;&#x40;&#x70;&#x61;&#x75;&#108;&#x73;&#116;&#97;&#99;&#107;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x2e;&#x75;&#107;</a></a></p>

<h3>I love working on infrastructure!</h3>

<p>Over the past few years, I have helped transform a team who worked solely in the manual sysadmin space into the configuration management world. This has reduced the time taken to provision a server and get an application into production from a number of weeks, to a number of hours.</p>

<p>Metrics are a key part of my day to day work. I believe that if we don&rsquo;t measure it then we cannot improve on it and learn from it. I also love to know what is happening with my systems before getting a call from an end user telling me there is a problem.</p>

<p>I have a real drive to make the lives of the engineer teams I work with easier. This means that by helping to create better infrastructure practices, I am helping them and ultimately helping deliver more business value</p>

<h3>What type of company would I work for?</h3>

<p>I have learned over the past few years that being part of a good company is the key to a happy work life. Culture, to me, is absolutely everything. I deeply care about what I do and I really want to be part of a company that holds these same values.</p>

<p>Remote work is something I am interested in, as long as the company is set up for it. I worked remotely a lot in 2014 and found it to be hugely productive as well as beneficial for my previous company because it allowed me to interact to a greater scale with the wider engineer community learning and sharing best practices to keep at the forefront of the industry. I therefore don’t mind where in the world a company is based, but that company must value treating remote employees as importantly as those who are office based</p>

<h3>What about the role?</h3>

<p>I want to be part of a team that care about the systems they create. Working on challenging problems brings out the absolute best in me, and being successful in this means the team I belong to is hugely important because every single person has a role to play in finding and implementing solutions. Working with a team of engineers who always want to improve themselves, their work, and support their colleagues, is what drives me and helps create a supportive team dynamic. Therefore I want to work with engineers who have a good work/life balance and love what they do as much as I do.</p>

<h3>What I definitely don&rsquo;t want to do</h3>

<p>I don&rsquo;t want to be a ticket filler. I want to be involved in helping to shape infrastructure systems and helping to drive decisions going forward. In my opinion, automation is key to helping deliver great systems and I really want to be part of delivering those systems</p>

<h3>So hire me!</h3>

<p>If your company is looking for passionate infrastructure developers who always want to improve or If your company has a need (and the willingness) to drive their infrastructure forward and improve then I could be the right person for you.</p>

<p><a href="public@paulstack.co.uk"><a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#x3a;&#112;&#117;&#98;&#108;&#105;&#99;&#64;&#112;&#97;&#117;&#x6c;&#x73;&#116;&#x61;&#99;&#107;&#x2e;&#99;&#x6f;&#46;&#117;&#107;">&#x70;&#117;&#x62;&#x6c;&#x69;&#99;&#x40;&#x70;&#x61;&#x75;&#x6c;&#x73;&#116;&#97;&#99;&#107;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#46;&#x75;&#107;</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[IT Recruitment is F**ked]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2014/01/28/it-recruitment-is-f-star-star-ked/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-28T18:12:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2014/01/28/it-recruitment-is-f-star-star-ked</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We get inundated with job specs in our inbox. Each email is filled with buzzwords in order to try and entice us to take the new role. I have not, nor will not, take a job spec filled with buzzwords. I join a company because of a culture. Having recently read Simon Sinek&rsquo;s book, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Start-Why-Leaders-Inspire-Everyone/dp/1591846447">Start With Why</a>, I really started to see how recruitment in IT is <del>f**ked</del> broken. The book talks about manipulations in modern society. This sounds bad and that it&rsquo;s not something we are used to. It&rsquo;s something we are very used to. We see it everyday. Supermarkets offering &lsquo;buy 1 get 1 free&rsquo; on products. Car companies offering us &lsquo;£500 cashback&rsquo; when buying a new car. This is all manipulation to get us to buy things. How many of us have bought a second item at the supermarket as it is buy 1 get 1 half price?</p>

<p>IT recruitment also has a lot of manipulation in it. In the past, I applied for a job by giving my details to a recruiter. I have turned up for that specific interview to find I was interviewing for a job I didn&rsquo;t know about. A job I had no experience for. My CV had been changed to fit the spec the company had asked for. The recruiter was manipulating the company to get someone in the door. These types of things happen every day. I get emails in my inbox offering me &lsquo;John Smith&rsquo; at £250 a day. I am not a recruitment manager and I have never spoken to these companies. They are effectively fishing. Would you be happy knowing you are being used as a carrott for a recruitment company to get into a company?</p>

<p>It is because of this that I have a mistrust in most recruiters. Not all are bad. It feels as thought they manipulate us (companies) into working with them. I understand they are just trying to do their job. I just try not to use them. I would rather hire someone based on a referral from someone else. But even that can have manipulations to it though. How many of you get a referral bonus for bringing someone to your company? Are we doing it for the right reasons? I like to think I am and not for money</p>

<p>Consider the following, fake, job spec:</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Job Description:</strong> <br/>
Do you have strong experience in X and Y technologies? Are you interested in joining a strong team who do A, B and C?</p>

<p><strong>Skills &amp; Requirements:</strong><br/>
* 5 years experience in X<br/>
* Deep understanding of Agile<br/>
* 3 years experience in a technology only released this year<br/>
* Buzzword 1<br/>
* Buzzword 2<br/>
* etc.</p>

<p>If interested, then please contact, <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#58;&#109;&#101;&#x40;&#x62;&#117;&#122;&#122;&#119;&#x6f;&#114;&#100;&#114;&#101;&#x63;&#x72;&#117;&#105;&#116;&#x65;&#114;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x2e;&#x75;&#x6b;">&#109;&#x65;&#64;&#x62;&#x75;&#x7a;&#x7a;&#119;&#111;&#x72;&#x64;&#x72;&#101;&#99;&#x72;&#117;&#x69;&#x74;&#x65;&#114;&#46;&#x63;&#111;&#x2e;&#x75;&#107;</a></p>

<hr />

<p>This doesn&rsquo;t interest me in the slightest. I have no feel about what type of work I&rsquo;d be doing or who I&rsquo;d be working with. It stipulates the technologies I&rsquo;d be using to try and eliminate people up front.It doesn&rsquo;t tell me anything about the company or what they are trying to achieve. This type of advert is <strong>never</strong> going to entice me to join this company. I mentioned above that I would only join companies now because of culture. Culture is very important to me. I need to be working with smart people who challenge me or I get bored. I don&rsquo;t want to be bored.</p>

<p>In the book Start With Why, Simon Sinek continually reiterates &lsquo;people don&rsquo;t buy what you do, they buy why you do it&rsquo;. The example advert, above, would be from a company who can&rsquo;t sell why they do something. Maybe there don&rsquo;t understand it themselves. Not many companies can sell their &lsquo;Why&rsquo;. A few companies I know can do this are <a href="http://www.etsy.com/">Etsy</a>, <a href="http://tretton37.com/">Tretton37</a> and <a href="http://www.github.com/">Github</a>. The structure of a job spec from Etsy starts as follows:</p>

<p><strong>We build tools that enable our engineering team to safely deploy code to the Etsy website. These include the Continuous Integration (CI) system, xUnit frameworks, and functional testing suites. Everyone in the Product and Engineering teams can deploy code into production, on their own. We do this over 30 times every day. Release management is a role in which everyone on the team plays an active part, starting on their first day of work</strong></p>

<p>Straight away, before I read more than 1 paragraph, I understand what the values of their engineering team is. They then go on to talk about the team:</p>

<p><strong>The technical staff at Etsy believes that code is craft, good software and systems designs are works of art, and that the work we do is part of larger creative culture represented by the hundreds of thousands of inspired makers who make Etsy such a wondrous marketplace</strong></p>

<p>This helps solidify the culture they are telling me about and the engineers they hire to make this happen. They go on to say the following:</p>

<p><strong>Our current systems run PHP, Java, Python, Ruby, Solr/Lucene, Postgres, MySQL, and more.</strong></p>

<p>I could go on with the advert. It summed up the perfect job advertisement for me. This is the type of advert that would really get me interested in a job. I would join them for that culture. It isn&rsquo;t a job spec, it is an introduction to life at Etsy.</p>

<p>Are skills / technologies the most important thing to me when I hire someone? I used to think so. But now, it really isn&rsquo;t. If someone doesnt have passion or buy into the same values my company does then all the skills in the world may not help me fit in and work well. Skills can be taught. Communications, culture and passion can&rsquo;t (in my opinion).</p>

<p>It is important to say that not 100% of blame sits with recruiters. Companies, themselves, need to be much better towards their employees. After reading <a href="http://37signals.com/remote/">Remote</a>, the 37 signals book, I really started to see how somethings are being missed by companies themselves. Remote working is definitely 1 of them. I was never a fan of remote working. I would not want a remote worker in my team, until I started travelling a lot for work. Being remote from my team has really get better at communication and focus. I often will go to a conference and work remotely now. I am actually quite productive. I am writing this blog post on an 11 hour flight :).</p>

<p>To me, I don&rsquo;t think we, as compnaies, should care where you are based. We should allow our team members to work where they are most productive &ndash; if that happens to be in their home in the Swiss Alps then so be it. I understand there are legal hurdles when hiring remote workers. These are not insurmountable. It&rsquo;s important to say that companies like Github and Etsy have staff all over the world. American companies with staff in UK, Australia, New Zealand etc. Nothing is impossible.</p>

<p>Staff benefits are another piece of the puzzle required to help recruit people. Too many job specs say things like &lsquo;subsidised gym membership&rsquo; or &lsquo;healthcare&rsquo; included. What if I have my own gym membership or my own private healtcare? Can&rsquo;t I choose something else to help me during my time at that company? Again, the Remote book helped me to see that this is important. At 37 signals, staff are offered a family holiday or cooking school experience etc. This becomes part of their benefits package. That is much more useful to someone who has healthcare and gym membership already. It also helps the employee feel really valued</p>

<p>Everything I write about here is the result of creating a good culture and a sense of understanding of Why we do things rather than what we do. Culture is a tough thing to breed but when you do get there it seems as though it&rsquo;s really worth it. We need to keep hiring people to vreed that culture, people who buy into it. It&rsquo;s 2014, we should be better at hiring people. There are a lot of skilled people out there &ndash; it&rsquo;s time to tap into that resource pool. It can help you create truly special products. Look to companies like Etsy, Github, Netflix, Puppetlabs etc. for inspiration on what we can do better in this space.</p>

<p>$0.02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can we fully trust online training courses?]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2014/01/11/can-we-fully-trust-online-training_courses/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-11T21:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2014/01/11/can-we-fully-trust-online-training_courses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>NOTICE: This post is not written to pick on any specific person or service. This is only my thoughts from speaking to people in the past few weeks</em></p>

<p>The online training industry seems to be a lucrative thing. I have heard rumours (unconfirmed! ) of authors earning 6 or 7 figure sums from training courses they have made and delivered. While part of me thinks, &ldquo;I really want a part of that&rdquo;, the other part of me thinks that I don&rsquo;t have the level of expertise to do it.</p>

<p>I (used to) blog a lot. I speak at a lot of conferences. I have even been known to ramble on a podcast or a screencast. In my opinion, I suggest others get involved in doing things like this. It creates a culture of sharing and exchanging information. I don&rsquo;t earn money for these activities. I feel like I can talk about what I am passionate about. I also feel as though I can talk about new things.</p>

<p>I also run training courses on continuous integration and delivery. I am paid for these. Since I am paid for these, I feel that the level of information I put into these courses needs to create value for the attendees. In order to deliver information that is useful, I <strong>really</strong> need to understand my subject matter. By no means do I consider myself an expert in continuous integration or continuous delivery. I do feel as though I have enough experience building these systems that I can pass my learnings off to other users.</p>

<p>The courses that I run are very much face to face. I listen to the attendees to see what they want to achieve and I tailor the content to give them that information. Online training courses do not do this, in my opinion. I have considered trying to record some material but I don&rsquo;t know if the information would be of use. My pet hate is when people record training material on subjects that they know very little about or have little understanding about.</p>

<p>I have seen places where individual people record lots and lots of courses. Of course, they get paid to do this. To me, this feels wrong. What gives those authors the right to disseminate information on a topic that they don&rsquo;t have a deep understanding of? The information they give may not be accurate &ndash; does the user get their money back if they watch a video on API design, follow it and causes a production outage?</p>

<p>Is the issue with the authors themselves or the training companies?</p>

<p>The same issue happens with books. I reviewed a lot of books in 2013. A lot of the books were excellent. Some of them were not very good at all. Book publishers are spamming potential authors trying to get them to write. This is a source of income for them (albet it low). But it&rsquo;s extra income all the same.</p>

<p>In my opinion, publishers have a contract with people who use their services. Get the best possible trainers for the subject. Don&rsquo;t put metrics above the level of service you give to your customers. Good training makes us all better at what we do. It&rsquo;s important we don&rsquo;t give developers / operations / managers a false understanding of topics. It can cause issues in a team and it can cause issues in our systems. I&rsquo;m not looking to name and shame people / companies here but I do expect a good level of service if I pay for something</p>

<p>&lt;/rant&gt;</p>

<p>I just learned that <a href="https://twitter.com/hhariri">Hadi Hariri</a> wrote a post on the <a href="http://hadihariri.com/2012/03/18/the-journey-of-teaching/">Journey of Teaching</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/thefringeninja">thefringeninja</a> for making sure this wasn&rsquo;t too ranty :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changing my focus]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2014/01/09/changing-my-focus/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T10:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2014/01/09/changing-my-focus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For those that know me, you know that I am very passionate about infrastructure and DevOps. Infrastructure is something that we, as developers, don&rsquo;t really give a lot of thought to. DevOps is something that will make our businesses more successful. So, I am changing the job role that I have.</p>

<p>From now, I am no longer focusing on writing application code. Instead I am going to spend my time focusing on the following areas:</p>

<ul>
<li>Be the facilitator to help our engineering team be much better by creating a DevOps culture</li>
<li>Writing code to control our infrastructure</li>
<li>Learning about the weird and wonderful ways of operations</li>
</ul>


<p>DevOps is very important to me. When a company has a great culture, things get done. Operations work is smooth, software delivery is smooth and the teams are truly focused on achieving the goals of the business. Without a DevOps culture, things are not as smooth as they could be. In order to allow our developers to more faster, we will be building better systems (e.g. provisioning, configuration management, monitoring, logging etc.) to allow them to really achieve &lsquo;situational awareness&rsquo;</p>

<p>I heard the term &lsquo;situational awareness&rsquo; just over a year ago. It was defined as &lsquo;knowing what is going on around you&rsquo;. Putting this into context, do you know what is going on with your applications in production? I certainly didn&rsquo;t. This is essential to understand how your software is performing. I will be trying to help our engineers to try and solve this issue by helping them build better infrastructure management systems.</p>

<p>Operations is something that I know very little about. By exposing myself to this world, I feel it will help me understand the continual frustrations that operations and development staff have towards each other.</p>

<p>As you can see, I am truly trying to be a DevOps advocate. I want to be the person that helps the teams talk to each other and help each other rather than (traditionally) having silos. I will still be trying to talk at developer events / conferences. I feel that I can really help developers understand more about DevOps and how it can be successful.</p>

<p>This is a very exciting change for me! Let&rsquo;s see how it goes&hellip;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why delay the VS2012 release, Microsoft?]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/08/09/why-delay-the-vs2012-release-microsoft/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/08/09/why-delay-the-vs2012-release-microsoft</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The date is 1st August 2012. Developers have been wondering for weeks when the release of VS2012 and ASP.NET 4.5 will happen. Somasegar, cvp of dev div in Microsoft, has just <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/somasegar/archive/2012/08/01/visual-studio-2012-and-net-4-5-complete.aspx" target="_blank">announced that the final build version of VS2012 is complete</a>.This means the product is ready for release. Dot net developers all over the world are eagerly waiting for the immortal words, &ldquo;it&rsquo;s available to download on MSDN&rdquo;. Unfortunately they haven&rsquo;t come. Instead, the download will not show up for another 14 days. This seems wasteful to me.</p>
<p>Tell me if I am incorrect, but I believe the delay is that the product has gone to tool vendors to make sure that their tools / plugins will work with the application. This to me seems a very strange thing to do. This product has technically been in the making for 18 months (since the release of VS2010) so giving it to vendors in the final 2 weeks is crazy. What will happen if the vendors report it doesn&rsquo;t work with their tools? Would Microsoft stop a release for this considering it is so baked into the windows 8 release? I don&rsquo;t think there is any possibility of that happening at all. Therefore why the delay? I understand that 3rd party vendors are customers that Microsoft have to satisfy, but technically so are we &ndash; the users of the product.</p>
<p>My ethos on software delivery is ship early, ship often. I hate when a feature is complete that it has to wait around for 2 weeks before release. Get the product out there, start gathering feedback and get planning to deliver more value to that customer. I understand that VS2012 is not easy to release often. Its a rather large download and there are pricing models around it. But changing the shape of the product to delivery in small chunks that are updatable more often would allow the product to get shaped by its user base. Faster feedback means delivering more customer value. It seems that other departments within Microsoft are now following this model (MVC team, EF team and Nuget team). Delivering like this is becoming more popular (and hopefully will become the standard). Its time to embrace this ethos Microsoft. Its certainly how I would be looking at things in the future if I were the product lead developer.</p>
<p>$0.02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Survival of the fittest – fluid teams?]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/06/25/survival-of-the-fittest-fluid-teams/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/06/25/survival-of-the-fittest-fluid-teams</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In traditional, waterfall organisations, a development team follows the organisation hierarchy. The development team can be split into smaller sub teams and each of those teams can have their own leader, but ultimately the hierarchy still exists. Developers usually stay in that sub team for most of their time in the organisation and they know exactly who their line manger is and who is responsible for their reviews and can act accordingly. The organisational structure is rigid and embedded into the process of the team and organisation.</p>
<p>In more agile teams, the organisational structure is less rigid meaning that developers do not need to stay in a single sub team for their time at the company. They can be organised (or organise themselves in more advanced agile cultures) into teams based on skills. New developers are hired with a view to how they can benefit the wider team and not towards the skills needed for a sub team in a waterfall environment. Even though there are less restrictions on people moving between teams, it is not always guaranteed. It can happen when required, e.g. when a new member of staff is hired and the skillsets need to be spread evenly. This can evolve further.</p>
<h4>Can agile teams be formed around projects?</h4>
<p>Simply, yes. This is actually how projects work at Facebook. When a developer joins the company, they can request what team they want to join when their &lsquo;boot camp&rsquo; is over. Each developer has a desk and that desk is on wheels. Their office is completely open plan. When a team&rsquo;s project is finished, the developers simply break up as a unit and wheel their desks to form the next team for the next project.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve talked to a few people about this fluid team structure. All responses seem to follow the questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>If a developer continually moves around, who is the manager responsible for the developers review?</li>
</ul>
<p>At school, I was part of a form group and I had a form tutor. This was the class I was part of each morning between 0900 and 0910 and where registration would be taken. I didn&rsquo;t study all my subjects with that class or that tutor. Each teacher had their own area of expertise. I moved around when I needed to go to a class. The same can happen in the workplace. In an agile team there should not be any need to micromanage members of the team. Just because you don&rsquo;t sit beside your line manager doesn&rsquo;t mean they cannot manage you. They need to form a trusting and communicative relationship with each other &ndash; characteristics of an agile team. This will allow the manager to know exactly how the developer is progressing and any obstacles in their way.</p>
<ul>
<li>What happens if a project ends up with all the weakest developers in a development department?</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are happy to hire weak developers then I suggest a look at your hiring process may be a useful thing to do. If a developer is not hired because they have the correct attitude, skillset and cultural fit for your team or you are happy to hire the &lsquo;best of a bad bunch&rsquo;&nbsp; then you may have bigger issues than worrying about the formation of sub teams.</p>
<p>To summarise, you don&rsquo;t need to keep developers locked to a team or a line manager. A trusting and communicative environment should always allow the team to focus on what they were hired for, the delivery of software. After all, if you are not here to care about the quality and standard of your work, then you should really think about changing career and stop wasting your employers money.</p>
<p>$0.02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TFS and Continuous Deployment]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/06/19/tfs-and-continuous-deployment/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/06/19/tfs-and-continuous-deployment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a huge advocate of continuous integration and continuous delivery. I am always cautious about mentioning continuous deployment in my talks. This <strong>can</strong>, I stress the word can, be dangerous. For me there is a journey in the delivery of software.</p>  <ul>   <li>Companies, traditionally, started slow and go with manual deployments infrequently </li>    <li>Continuous Integration was introduced to the team when the team grew and needed to help test the integration of their code </li>    <li>The need to deploy more frequently may arise and as manual deployments are time consuming and (or) painful, deployments become automated </li>    <li>Continuous delivery was then said to be the better way to develop software (this meaning that code in the master repo is always in a state where it can be released to the end user) </li> </ul>  <p>This journey not only required a development teams skillset to grow to support it, but it also required a culture and attitude change as we move through the lifecycle. Developers need to start taking more care in their work and making sure that technical debt is not accrued too fast and that work is tested thoroughly. For me, when a team reaches this maturity point, they have reached the pinnacle of software delivery. The time required to release a new feature (cycle time) is determined by how fast the developer can develop and test the feature rather than worrying about release cycles. A release for this individual can be created and scheduled as appropriate to the needs of the business. The process is almost completely automated.</p>  <p>Lets take the step to continuous deployment. This is where every successful build is released to the end user. For me, things start to get a bit scary here. Continuous deployment is associated with start-ups. Companies that are releasing a new product and need to get it to market fast to get revenue and user feedback. As the codebase is young, it would has accrued less technical debt so the cycle time would potentially be faster than companies with legacy code. I believe that continuous deployment needs to be surrounded by rigorous automated testing (unit, integration, acceptance, system, performance etc..) and also supported by an immune system that helps to notify everyone if key performance or conversion metrics etc. drop below certain thresholds. This would help the confidence in the code being released to be as high as possible. In this type of environment, developers should work with the operations staff to make sure that deployments happen and follow up if there are issues with the release. I cannot stress enough that continuous deployment should not be taken lightly. It *will* come back and bit you on the ass if you are not well prepared.</p>  <p>Imagine my surprise when I read on twitter during the (azure announcement name hashtag) that the new version of TFS will support continuously deploying applications to the new azure portal [THIS NEEDS CHECKED FOR ACCURACY]. Firstly, I was surprised that this feature was added to TFS over something more useful, e.g. DVCS style version control. The lack of the good version control is a major downfall in TFS for me. Secondly, I think that this new feature will inspire a new breed of false bravery. I understand that it is very good to be brave. Nothing is braver than finishing development fast and pushing straight to production. There needs to be a process around these deployments – are they dark deployments, canary releases, have A/B testing etc.? Have you got the performance test analysis incase your feature causes an issue in production that costs the company money. Have you got monitoring around the system to spot potential issues early. There are many things I have set up around my continuous deployment sites.I don’t believe that all software developers give enough thought to what they are doing and will fix it later. Continuous deployment may not be good for these types of developer. A small issue unnoticed, e.g. a missing ‘checkout’ button on the site, can cause the company a lot of money. </p>  <p>I am by no way trying to say my setup is better than other developer setups, I am merely pointing out that a good support network around a deployment is needed. Maybe azure has this good support network but a developer should definitely know how to use it if they are to take advantage of this feature. If you are working on a personal project that doesn’t affect too much then continuously deploy until your heart is content. If wanting to take the giant leap to this in a company with legacy code then think twice. don’t f**k with your users. They potentially pay your salary. I think TFS should focus on making the tool easier to use for developers rather than worry about continuous deployment just yet</p>  <p>&lt;/TFSRant&gt;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is your interpretation of burnout?]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/06/07/what-is-your-interpretation-of-burnout/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/06/07/what-is-your-interpretation-of-burnout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I always had the idea that the term &lsquo;burnout&rsquo; had a pretty standard meaning in software development. I&rsquo;m sure each developer have their own way of phrasing it but in essence, I was always of the idea that it meant &lsquo;over working leading to exhaustion and lack of motivation&rsquo;.</p>
<p>I wanted to see what the exact thoughts of my peers was so asked on twitter &ldquo;what does burnout meant to you?&rdquo;. I got a list of varied responses:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.twitter.com/tomasmcguinness" target="_blank">@tomasmcguinness</a>: <em>Burnout in terms of software development? For me, it means losing the ability to concentrate and focus,combined with mental fatigue</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.twitter.com/mbrit" target="_blank">@mbrit</a>: <em>For me, it&#8217;s about ending up at a dead end in terms of stimulation/career progress.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.twitter.com/kristofclaes" target="_blank">@kristofclaes</a>: <em>&#8220;I should have kept this as a hobby&#8230;&#8221; or something like that. Not sure how to put it into words.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.twitter.com/jcmm33" target="_blank">@jcmm33</a>: <em>whatever the cause, its a lack of focus/motivation/drive/engagement within an employee when there used to be</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.twitter.com/nathangloyn" target="_blank">@NathanGloyn</a>: <em>burnout = not able to work any more, nervous breakdown, catastrophic event</em></p>
<p>These are only a few of the responses, but as you can see the vary a lot. The reason I asked this question is that whilst on a trip to San Francisco recently, I was able to catch a company organised talk from <a href="http://www.facebook.com/jayp" target="_blank">Jay Parikh</a>, the VP of Infrastructure at Facebook. I don&rsquo;t need to tell you who Facebook are therefore you can imagine I was very interested to hear his thoughts on the subject. Whilst talking to us, Jay spoke about Facebook hack-a-thons. Basically their entire team (product owners, devs, IT guys etc.) get together on a night of the week in the Facebook campus and work on something they don&#8217;t normally work on.</p>
<p>One of our developers asked the question, &ldquo;how do your devs avoid burnout when approaching hack-a-thons in the middle of a work week?&rdquo;. Jay discussed that development at Facebook wasn&rsquo;t a strict 9 &ndash; 5 culture and that developers would work the hours that they felt quite at home with. He said the developers at Facebook don&rsquo;t suffer burnout as <em>&ldquo;burnout is loosing interest in a project or piece of work&rdquo;</em> and their developers work for a maximum of 12 months in a team before moving to another.</p>
<p>I can see Jay&rsquo;s point but I don&rsquo;t feel that working too much and losing interest on a project are mutually exclusive. I think if you work too much then you can become bogged down in feeling a bit frustrated in your work. This can create boredom and make you lose interest and (or) focus. This is where I think burnout creeps in. This is what we need to make sure we avoid when we plan work. I usually associate burnout with long waterfall projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TeamCity - OutOfMemoryError]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/05/21/teamcity-outofmemoryerror/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/05/21/teamcity-outofmemoryerror</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whilst upgrading our TeamCity server from 6.5 to 7.x, I encountered an error:</p>
<p><em>Unexpected error occurred inside Alarm task: java.lang.OutOfMemoryError: GC overhead limit exceeded</em></p>
<p>After a bit of looking around and sifting through some very weird articles I was able to find some good information on this. Basically, the JVM starts by default with 512mb of memory and it was struggling to process our 300+ build configurations with this. In order to fix it I had to do the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Go to TeamCity webserver</li>
<li>Open CMD</li>
<li>cd &lt;TeamCity root dir&gt;</li>
<li>cd bin</li>
<li>teamcity7w.exe //ES//TeamCity
<ul>
<li>If you are on TeamCity 6.x then you need to run teamcity6w.exe rather than ..7w</li>
</ul>
</li>
This will open the following dialog:</ul>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_51.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_49.png" alt="image" width="244" height="233" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>Go to the Java tab and change the maximum memory pool entry to something other than 512mb</p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_52.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_50.png" alt="image" width="244" height="233" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>Restart the service and all should be well with the application start-up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing TeamCityMetro for WP7]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/05/17/introducing-teamcity-metro/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/05/17/introducing-teamcity-metro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After my foray into the work of the <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/teamcity/" target="_blank">TeamCity</a> API, <a href="http://twitter.com/gep13" target="_blank">Gary Park</a> and I have written a WP7 app. We are pleased to announce that this app is now available in the <a href="http://stack72.me/teamcitymetrowp" target="_blank">AppStore</a> and is FREE to all. For version 1, the application will only give you the opportunity to see your projects, builds types, last 10 builds of each build type and then link to the build on your teamcity server. This is only an initial release and will be followed up with the ability to trigger builds.</p>
<p>The application looks as follows:</p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot1_1.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="Screenshot1" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot1_thumb_1.png" alt="Screenshot1" width="148" height="244" border="0" /></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot2_1.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="Screenshot2" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot2_thumb_1.png" alt="Screenshot2" width="148" height="244" border="0" /></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot3_1.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="Screenshot3" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot3_thumb_1.png" alt="Screenshot3" width="148" height="244" border="0" /></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot4_1.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="Screenshot4" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot4_thumb_1.png" alt="Screenshot4" width="148" height="244" border="0" /></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot5_1.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="Screenshot5" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot5_thumb_1.png" alt="Screenshot5" width="148" height="244" border="0" /></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot6_1.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="Screenshot6" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot6_thumb_1.png" alt="Screenshot6" width="148" height="244" border="0" /></a>&nbsp; <a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot7_1.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="Screenshot7" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/Screenshot7_thumb_1.png" alt="Screenshot7" width="148" height="244" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>If you want to request a feature or leave us some feedback then please get in touch with us. An application website will soon appear. All feedback gratefully received. Huge thanks to all our beta testers. Without them this application would never have made it past beta.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enum String Value with JQuery Mobile]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/05/03/enum-string-value-for-use-with-jquery-mobile/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/05/03/enum-string-value-for-use-with-jquery-mobile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A while back I had to use <a href="http://jquerymobile.com/" target="_blank">JQuery mobile</a> for a project. The project needed to have 2 themes on an application and the configuration would need to tell the application what theme to load. With JQuery Mobile, the theme string could only be a single letter. I like keeping to decent and meaningful naming conventions, so I created a configuration setting as follows:</p>
<p>&lt;add key=&#8221;Theme&#8221; value=&#8221;Plain&#8221; /&gt;</p>
<p>I could see easily that the theme for this build of the application is the Plain theme. How could I relate that back to a JQuery theme? Plain would not be acceptable with JQuery Mobile. Therefore I had to do something different. I was able to use an attribute on the Theme Enum:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/87a15d10b39c4ab6f26a.js"></script>
<p>I then overrode the WebViewPage to include logic to get the Theme as follows:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/cdd00afc29b4b4599ebb.js"></script>
<p>As you can see, I have an extension method in place to get the string value of the enum. This then taps back into my String attribute as follows:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/94a594f634ee0aa1e3ae.js"></script>
<p>This then allowed me to turn a simple readable string from a web.config, into something that JQuery Mobile could understand and parse as normal</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You think I'm doing it wrong, so help me do it right]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/05/01/you-think-im-doing-it-wrong-so-help-me-do-it-right/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/05/01/you-think-im-doing-it-wrong-so-help-me-do-it-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am fed up with reading more and more posts, mostly on twitter, telling me I&rsquo;m wrong if I&rsquo;m doing it this way or wrong if I&rsquo;m not using this tool. Who gives you the right to tell me I am not correct? You do not know my problem space, domain or the criteria I need to work towards.</p>
<p>I have to say that this post is not in retaliation to anyone telling me I am doing something wrong. It is based towards all the posts titled &lsquo;You&rsquo;re doing it wrong&hellip;.&rsquo;</p>
<p>In my opinion, we are continually learning in this industry. Something you may be good at now, may not be the hot topic in 6 months time. I am not sure there is a single person who knows <strong>*everything*</strong>. You may have your niche of expertise and you may be able to help but be constructive. If you really think I am doing it wrong, then give me reasons why so and point out the flaws in my way. It isn&rsquo;t black and white. This is not a math problem &ndash; there may be more than 1 way to do something.</p>
<p>I do a lot of speaking to groups about continuous integration &amp; delivery. There is no way I would tell someone they are wrong. Instead, all I can do is to put the reasons out there for my way of doing something. If the person takes this on-board then that&#8217;s fantastic. If they don&#8217;t, I won&#8217;t get offended. Maybe we should focus on helping the devs who are supposedly doing it wrong rather than pointing that almighty finger at them. Who knows, you may even learn something yourself.</p>
<p>&lt;/rant&gt;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spoofing the Host Entry in a HTTPWebRequest]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/04/30/spoofing-the-host-entry-in-a-httpwebrequest/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/04/30/spoofing-the-host-entry-in-a-httpwebrequest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had this idea to create a dashboard that would ping different version of a site in order to get the build number. The details are as follows:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mysite.com">www.mysite.com</a></p>
<p>runs on a local site at 192.x.x.x, a QA environment at 10.x.x.x, a staging environment at 66.x.x.x, and a live environment at 88.x.x.x (these IPs are made up). In order to hit each site, I would usually manually change the host file and then make the web request. This was not a great solution as I hate dealing with host file entries. On experimenting with HTTPWebRequest, I noticed that you can use reflection in order to change the Headers of the Request. The normal code to create a HTTPWebRequest would look as follows:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/17bf91700d77d25c2435.js"></script>
<p>I was able to spoof the host by changing the host using reflection:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/5eb2fcb26600cd81416c.js"></script>
<p>This allowed me to make multiple requests to different versions of the same site. Using a simple collection of my site objects to build a dashboard that had the following outline:</p>
<table style="width: 574px;" border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="116">&nbsp;</td>
<td valign="top" width="118">Local</td>
<td valign="top" width="110">QA</td>
<td valign="top" width="113">Stage</td>
<td valign="top" width="115">Live</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="115">Build Number</td>
<td valign="top" width="118">web_12_4_qa</td>
<td valign="top" width="111">web_12_4_qa</td>
<td valign="top" width="114">web_12_5_stg</td>
<td valign="top" width="116">web_12_4_prod</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My approach to refactoring a monster switch statement]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/04/15/my-approach-to-refactoring-a-monster-switch-statement/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/04/15/my-approach-to-refactoring-a-monster-switch-statement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had to refactor some very old code a while back. The code looked similar to this:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/02f6a05870b5b2dd277f.js"></script>
<p>I had to refactor it so that I could add more parts to it. There was no way I could add in more case statements so it all had to go. I took a cautious approach to the refactoring as it was pretty brittle and quite important code. The first step in refactoring made the code look as follows:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/e263574855d5dc9b19fd.js"></script>
<p>This mean that I could make sure that the function of the code didn&rsquo;t change but that it was easier to read. This still couldn&rsquo;t be unit tested though as there was no way to mock the behaviour of the case statements &ndash; it was all still in the same class. The next refactoring step was to allow some unit tests to be written. I was able to separate the behaviours into their own class and made the code look as follows:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/ce53ce246dcf5f9bcaaa.js"></script>
<p>This wasn&rsquo;t enough for me. I still had this huge switch statement that was breaking the <a href="http://www.objectmentor.com/resources/articles/ocp.pdf" target="_blank">Open / Closed principle</a>. This meant that in order to add more functionality to the switch, I had to change the switch and risk breaking it. This couldn&rsquo;t happen. This made my final part of the code look as similar:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/843ed2eeaf5fab2e3c7f.js"></script>
<p>With this code I could make sure that I could write some unit tests around the behaviour of the class. This post only talks about going this far. I have since refactored the TaskRunner class much more as it was doing a lot more than 1 thing and thus breaking <a href="http://www.objectmentor.com/resources/articles/srp.pdf" target="_blank">SRP</a>. How would you have handled the same refactoring?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom blogging workflow with YouTrack]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/04/09/custom-blogging-workflow-with-youtrack/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/04/09/custom-blogging-workflow-with-youtrack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past week, I have started using <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/youtrack" target="_blank">YouTrack</a>&nbsp;3.0 in the cloud as a think tank of blog posts that I want to write. Previously I had used Trello. there was no particular reason for moving away from <a href="http://trello.com">Trello</a> other than curiosity about what YouTrack could offer me. On setting up YouTrack I added a project to start the tracking of the blog posts. On adding the first post, I was given the following state workflow:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_41.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_39.png" alt="image" width="419" height="227" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>As you can see, you can pretty much change the state to be any other out of the box. I wanted to use this as the opportunity to create a custom workflow for YouTrack. I was able to download the <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/youtrack/download/" target="_blank">YouTrack Workflow Editor</a> and start the editor. <a href="http://twitter.com/hhariri" target="_blank">Hadi Hariri</a> has created a post on the basics of the workflow editor on <a href="http://hadihariri.com/2012/02/15/spicing-up-youtrack-with-workflows/" target="_blank">his blog</a> but this was only to create a stateless rule. I wanted to create a &lsquo;statemachine&rsquo; rule. Basically the flow was to be as follows:</p>
<p>- Initially the issue created would be assigned to &lsquo;To Write&rsquo;</p>
<p>- Issues in &lsquo;To Write&rsquo; could be changed to &lsquo;In Draft&rsquo;</p>
<p>- Issues in &lsquo;In Draft&rsquo; could be changed to &lsquo;In Review&rsquo; when complete or &lsquo;To Write&rsquo; when paused</p>
<p>- Issues in &lsquo;In Review- can be changed to &lsquo;Published&rsquo; when closed or &lsquo;In Draft&rsquo; when failed review</p>
<p>I immediately got to work and created a new rule as in Hadi&rsquo;s post but this time I chose a statemachine rule. This gave me the following template:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_42.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_40.png" alt="image" width="447" height="240" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>I had to add the first transition. That when initially opened the state would be &lsquo;To Write&rsquo;:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_43.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_41.png" alt="image" width="447" height="240" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>I then had to implement the changes allowed to State from &lsquo;To Write&rsquo;. This says that when an issue in To Write, the only state it can move to is &lsquo;In Draft&rsquo;. As you can see, there is a stub of the state for In Draft created now by the Editor. I was then able to say that when the post is In Draft, it can move to In Review when finished writing or To Write when paused:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_44.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_42.png" alt="image" width="427" height="230" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>I was then able to implement that when the post is In Review, it could change to Published when verified or In Draft when it didn&rsquo;t pass review. This gave us the stub for Published. As there were no state changes allowed when published, I just had to leave the Published state empty as shown:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_45.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_43.png" alt="image" width="425" height="229" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>After uploading the workflow to the server, as per Hadi&rsquo;s instructions, I then had to attached the workflow to my project. I went to administration and chose the project type and then the workflow tab, I clicked the button &lsquo;Attach workflow&rsquo;. This game me the following:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_46.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_44.png" alt="image" width="422" height="229" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>I just had to choose the workflow I had created (stack72-blogging-stateflow) and I could then see the transition screens were working as appropriate:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_47.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_45.png" alt="image" width="146" height="133" border="0" /></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_48.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_46.png" alt="image" width="151" height="133" border="0" /></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_49.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_47.png" alt="image" width="153" height="133" border="0" /></a>&nbsp;<a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_50.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_48.png" alt="image" width="148" height="133" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>This was very easy. I must pay credit to the Youtrack team for such a simple workflow editor. IT has intellisense and was able to offer me all sorts of options on clicking control + spacebar together. Thanks also to Hadi&rsquo;s post for introducing me to the Workflow editor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agile teams and working from home]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/04/03/agile-teams-and-working-from-home/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/04/03/agile-teams-and-working-from-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday (April 2nd 2012), I posed a question on twitter:</p>  <p><strong>Does anyone think that people working from home in an agile team is a bad idea?</strong></p>  <p>This seemed to be quite a controversial question to pose. My favourite response was “isn’t agile – as long as you get the work done, doesn’t matter home, office, card, no-cards, no??” Now, I can see what the author <a href="http://twitter.com/edonsojeva" target="_blank">(@edonsojeva)</a> is trying to say. I agree that one of the main principles of agile is getting work done. But, on the other hand, for me the best principle of agile is the ability to communicate with members of the team <strong>*and*</strong> the business. IM clients (Skype, Lync, MSN etc.) are a great way to keep in touch. But I have never found them to be fantastically efficient at being able to display the entire picture. When speaking to people I want to see them face to face (where possible). this allows us both to focus on the issue at hand.</p>  <p>when working remotely, people can get distracted. That’s just our nature. It doesn’t matter whether we get distracted by emails, twitter, other IM conversations happening at the same time or TV (yes I have seen this happen to some people), it happens. I find that that level of distraction is less in the office. Why email someone when you can get up from your desk, walk 10feet and speak to them and strike up a conversation instead? </p>  <p>I understand that it can sometimes be very important to isolate yourself just to get a few hours of no distraction. Being at home, with no one round can give you this isolation. My thoughts here are that if you do have so much to do that requires you to be isolated from the rest of the team, that you a) haven’t planned very well or b) are not agile. Team is the key word here. For me working from home takes away that sense of being part of the team. It can just make you feel a little isolated. Architecture and code can be a bit of a beast sometimes. It can therefore take other people to wind in crazy ideas. Unless you are this incredibly focused person, you can sometimes go off in a tangent or with an idea that another has already tried. It can also save time. If you run into an issue, a team member who has been in this situation before can point out a fix.</p>  <p>This leads me to the general idea that working from home is the exception rather than the rule. I wouldn’t be fantastically happy with members of the team who constantly worked from home. They would feel more like remote contractors than anything else. I understand there are incredibly focused individuals out there that can block out all these impediments and work from home efficiently. I am in no way saying that it isn’t possible. This post is merely a scratch pad to get feedback on what others have experienced.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TeamCitySharp now builds with Mono]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/02/08/teamcitysharp-now-builds-with-mono/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/02/08/teamcitysharp-now-builds-with-mono</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am pleased to be able to say that <a href="http://github.com/stack72/TeamCitySharp" target="_blank">TeamCitySharp</a> is now supports <a href="http://www.mono-project.com/" target="_blank">mono</a>. In order to get the project supported I had to change a few parts of the system.</p>
<p>Up until now, each project within the solution has a &ldquo;BeforeBuild&rdquo; event that downloaded the nuget packages needed to build the solution. This was in place to keep the github repository small enough to facilitate a fast download for people who fork it. <a href="http://www.nuget.org" target="_blank">Nuget</a> doesn&rsquo;t work with mono so there was a trade off I had to make. In this instance I chose supporting mono over the &ldquo;BeforeBuild&rdquo; event. This does mean that once the repository is cloned or forked. then it will work instantly. I hope to revisit this if / when someone manages to get nuget working with mono.</p>
<p>The sample build monitor was a standard ASP.NET MVC 3 project. I found that this didn&rsquo;t build with mono out of the box. It was throwing errors due to the references contained. The following references were present:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/before.gif"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="before" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/before_thumb.gif" alt="before" width="189" height="317" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>On running a reference analysis, I was able to see that the following references were not used:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/ToRemove.gif"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="ToRemove" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/ToRemove_thumb.gif" alt="ToRemove" width="240" height="227" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>This meant that only the core references were left behind. This meant that the entire solution was able to build under mono.</p>
<p>In order to build the project with mono, you can run the following command: <br /><strong>xbuild TeamCitySharp.sln</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Mono on Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/01/31/installing-mono-on-windows/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/2012/01/31/installing-mono-on-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have recently been thinking about making <a href="http://github.com/stack72/TeamCitySharp">TeamCitySharp</a> supported on <a href="http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page">mono</a>. This would require me to either run a VM (that you can download form the mono project site) or install mono on Windows. As I would continue to develop TeamCitySharp in VS2010, I thought it would be better to install mono on windows.</p>
<p>When trying to install mono, I went to the mono project download page and was presented with 3 options for windows:</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_39.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="image" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/image_thumb_37.png" alt="image" width="368" height="288" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>I had no idea what to install &amp; tweeted to that effect. Almost immediately, <a href="http://twitter.com/ferventcoder">Rob Reynolds</a> tweeted this back:</p>
<p><strong>cinst mono</strong></p>
<p>This is a reference to chocolatey which I have used before. <a href="http://chocolatey.org/">Chocolatey</a> is described as &ldquo;apt-get for windows&rdquo;. In order to install mono I had a number of steps to follow:</p>
<p>1. Set the execution policy of PowerShell to unrestricted</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/execution-policy.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="execution-policy" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/execution-policy_thumb.png" alt="execution-policy" width="308" height="159" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>2. Install chocolatey</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/chocolatey-install.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="chocolatey-install" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/chocolatey-install_thumb.png" alt="chocolatey-install" width="313" height="173" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>3. cinst mono</p>
<p><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/mono-install-1.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="mono-install-1" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/mono-install-1_thumb.png" alt="mono-install-1" width="313" height="173" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>which, when downloaded triggers the install</p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/mono-install-2.png"><img style="background-image: none; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-top: 0px; border: 0px;" title="mono-install-2" src="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/images/mono-install-2_thumb.png" alt="mono-install-2" width="283" height="220" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>Mono is now installed and ready to be used. This was extremely easy using chocolatey. I have used it before to install <a href="http://nodejs.org/">nodejs</a> but I have to admit I didn&#8217;t really pay attention to what packages it contained. I will be doing so from now on. If you have not checked out chocolatey then please do so &ndash; it rocks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
